Magdy Yacoub Abdo

Giza, Egypt | Phone: +20 1211017749 | Landline: +20 2 35433239 magdyyakob32@gmail.com | LinkedIn Link | GitHub Link

WORK SUMMARY

Quality-oriented software engineer with 3 years of practical and professional experience in application development using Flutter. I have experience developing over 10 Flutter applications with various designs and databases, as well as using REST API and Firebase.

EDUCATION

Ain Shams University

Cairo, Egypt

Graduation Date: October 2021 Bachelor of Computer Science

University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee

Wisconsin, United states

graduation Date: December 2019

Student exchange program (Fall semester)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Upwork

Flutter Developer – Remote

Jan 2022 – Present

- Developed and implemented cross-platform mobile applications using Flutter framework, resulting in a seamless user experience on both iOS and Android platforms.
- Integrated third-party APIs to enhance app functionality and ensure optimal performance.
- Implemented state management solutions such as Provider or Bloc to efficiently manage and update the application state.

MagedSoft

Flutter Developer – Internship

May 2021 - Jun 2021

- As a member of a team of developers, we developed responsive and high-performing applications, utilizing REST API for communication with the data source.
- Collaborated with backend developers to integrate front-end components with server-side logic and databases.

National Bank of Egypt

IT Agent

Jul 2019 – Aug 2019

 As an IT agent, I have had the privilege of assisting employees with their technical issues over the phone or through remote access.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Est App

Jan 2022 – Mar 2022

• Est app offers a solution for buyers and sellers to rent vaults located throughout Spain to place products for retrieval at their convenience.

• The Est app was developed using cutting-edge Flutter and Firebase technology.

Priest Assistant

Jan 2021 – Present

- The Priest Assistant app helps priests manage church attendees' records efficiently.
- The app was built using Flutter and utilizes the Flutter Hive database and Provider package for state management.

Rick & Morty

Sep 2023 – Present

• The app was specifically created to enhance my proficiency in utilizing Flutter bloc state management and the MVVM design pattern.

COURSES & SKILLS

Programming Languages: Dart, Java, C++, C#, and Python.

Frameworks and Tools: Flutter, Firebase, REST API, SQL, Hive, Git, VS Code, Android Studio, and Keras.

Courses: English courses, Leadership courses, and soft skills courses (Amideast Egypt).

Online Courses: Flutter Development Bootcamp with Dart, Google Cloud platform (GCP) fundamentals

Meta Android Developer Professional Certificate (In Progress).

Problem Solving: Analytical Thinking, Debugging, Intermediate problem solving skills (4-stars on Hacker Rank).

Linux: Intermediate level at using Linux.

Languages: Arabic (Native Language), English (Upper intermediate).

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Startup Land Summit 2020

2 months – IT specialist

• I was responsible for overseeing the registration process and providing technical support to both attendees and speakers during the online edition.

Misr El Kheir Foundation

20 Hours

• I was responsible for typing and formatting scanned English books into a specific style and format to be printed in braille language.

TDH Child Club

35 Hours

• I had the opportunity to work as a child mentor for a club that was focused on providing support to underprivileged children. This program was overseen by UNICEF.

HONORS

Educational Scholarship: U.S.- Egypt Higher Education Initiative (HEI) Public University Scholarship, Amideast, Egypt.

CERTIFICATIONS

In 2021, I scored 945/990 on the TOEIC Listening and Reading test, attaining an international professional proficiency level.

In 2020, I achieved a B2-level TOEFL ITP certification with a score of 590/677.